The hottest chick in town just switched bodies with
the luckiest loser in the world.
The Hot Chick is a comedy, fantasy film directed by Tom Brady.
Not only is Jessica Spencer the most popular girl in
school -- she is also the meanest.
But things change for the attractive teen when a freak accident involving a cursed pair of earrings and a
chance encounter at a gas station causes her to switch bodies with Clive, a sleazy crook.
Jessica, in the form of the repulsive Clive, struggles to adjust to this radical
alteration and sets out to get her own body back before the upcoming prom.
Jessica, played by Rob Schneider.
April, played by Anna Faris.
Billy, played by Matthew Lawrence.
Jake, played by Eric Christian Olsen.
Stan, played by Robert Davi.
Carol, played by Melora Hardin.
The Hot Chick is a 2002 American fantasy comedy film directed by Tom Brady, written by Brady and Rob Schneider, and
starring Schneider, Anna Faris, Matthew Lawrence, Eric Christian Olsen, Robert Davi and Michael O'Keefe.
The film follows Jessica Spencer, a mean-spirited cheerleader who
switches bodies with incompetent criminal Clive Maxtone.
When Jessica discovers that the switch was caused by a pair of enchanted earrings she had stolen, she enlists
the help of her friends to get the earrings back together before the switch becomes permanent.
Adam Sandler served as executive producer and made an uncredited cameo appearance as the Mambuza
Bongo Player, a character based on one played by Schneider on Saturday Night Live.
Principal photography began in March 2002 in Los Angeles and concluded in May.
The Hot Chick was theatrically released in the United States on December
13, 2002, and grossed $55 million against a $34M budget.
It received generally negative reviews from critics.
The film explores themes of sexual identity, high
school, friendship, jewelry, identity.
The tone is lighthearted.